<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "../../page.dtd">
<page xmlns:ac="http://www.atlassian.com/schema/confluence/4/ac/" xmlns:ri="http://www.atlassian.com/schema/confluence/4/ri/">
  <space>storage</space>
  <title>Guide Lines for General Operations</title>
  <lower-title>guide lines for general operations</lower-title>
  <body><hr /><p><strong>BEST PRACTICES FOR PULL REQUESTS (PR)</strong>  <br /><strong>WHAT SHOULD BE CONTAINED IN A PR</strong></p><ul><li><p>PRs should be specific — aimed toward a single user story and not contain multiple unrelated changes.  </p><ul><li><p>Exceptions would be when refactoring, but even refactors should have some order.</p></li></ul></li><li><p>PR should have an attached Work Item.</p></li></ul><hr /><h3>HOW TO ENSURE WE HAVE REVIEWERS FOR PR</h3><ul><li><p>As a minimum, two reviewers are required for a PR.  </p></li><li><p>To ensure all PRs are addressed, we should implement a rotation system.</p></li></ul><p>Got it, Pravesh. Here&apos;s the extracted text from your image:</p><hr /><p><strong>INTEGRATIONS SPRINT RULES (WIP)</strong>  </p><h3>✅ TASK CREATION RULES</h3><ul><li><p>All tasks added must have:  </p><ul><li><p><strong>Estimates</strong>  </p></li><li><p><strong>Time Spent</strong>  </p></li><li><p><strong>Time Remaining</strong>  <br />This helps ensure accurate burndown tracking.</p></li></ul></li><li><p>Once all user stories for the sprint are complete, <strong>additional tasks from user stories</strong> can be added.</p></li><li><p>A <strong>training task</strong> will be added to every sprint to ensure consistent time allocation for learning.  </p><ul><li><p>If user stories are complete, <strong>additional time can be used for training</strong>.  </p></li><li><p>If training is needed for a specific story, the <strong>training task will be linked to that story</strong>.</p></li></ul></li><li><p>When adding <strong>new high-priority (urgent) stories</strong> to the current sprint:  </p><ul><li><p><strong>Move lower priority stories</strong> to the next sprint.</p></li></ul></li></ul><hr /><p><strong>ACCEPTANCE CRITERIA FOR INTEGRATIONS TEAM TO ESTIMATE WORK EFFORT</strong>  </p><ol start="1"><li><p><strong>Requirements must be properly defined</strong> (this includes functional and non-functional requirements).  </p></li><li><p><strong>Downstream dependencies</strong> must either:  </p><ul><li><p>Have their functionality defined, or  </p></li><li><p>Have the complete system implemented and available.  </p></li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Proper documentation must exist for dependencies.</strong>  </p></li><li><p><strong>If decisions are still being made on dependencies</strong>, this should be flagged as a <strong>risk</strong> (outside our control) when estimating work.</p></li></ol><hr /><p /><p /></body>
  <category>storage-team</category>
  <category>confluence</category>
</page>
