<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "../../page.dtd">
<page xmlns:ac="http://www.atlassian.com/schema/confluence/4/ac/" xmlns:ri="http://www.atlassian.com/schema/confluence/4/ri/">
  <space>storage</space>
  <title>Typical Layers for Microservice Architecture</title>
  <lower-title>typical layers for microservice architecture</lower-title>
  <body><hr /><p><strong>INTEGRATIONS TYPICAL LAYERS FOR MICROSERVICE ARCHITECTURE</strong></p><p><strong>PRESENTATION LAYER</strong>  </p><ul><li><p>This layer handles the user interface and interaction with the microservices.  </p></li><li><p>It can include components like web APIs, user interfaces, and mobile applications.</p></li></ul><p><strong>API GATEWAY LAYER</strong>  </p><ul><li><p>The API gateway acts as a single entry point for clients to access the microservices.  </p></li><li><p>It handles authentication, routing, load balancing, and other cross-cutting concerns.</p></li></ul><p><strong>SERVICE LAYER</strong>  </p><ul><li><p>This layer contains the individual microservices that encapsulate specific business capabilities.  </p></li><li><p>Each microservice is responsible for a specific task or functionality.  </p></li><li><p>Microservices can be developed, deployed, and scaled independently.</p></li></ul><p><strong>BUSINESS LOGIC LAYER</strong>  </p><ul><li><p>This layer contains the core business logic of the microservices.  </p></li><li><p>It processes requests, implements business rules, and orchestrates interactions between different microservices.</p></li></ul><p><strong>DATA ACCESS LAYER</strong>  </p><ul><li><p>This layer is responsible for interacting with the underlying data storage systems, such as databases or external APIs.  </p></li><li><p>It handles data retrieval, storage, and manipulation.</p></li></ul><p><strong>INFRASTRUCTURE LAYER</strong>  </p><ul><li><p>This layer includes the infrastructure required to run microservices.  </p></li><li><p>Examples include servers, containers, networking, and monitoring tools.</p></li></ul><p /><ac:image ac:align="center" ac:layout="center" ac:original-height="1024" ac:original-width="1024" ac:custom-width="true" ac:alt="Visual MicroService.png" ac:width="760"><ri:attachment ri:filename="Visual MicroService.png" ri:version-at-save="1" /></ac:image><p /><hr /><p /></body>
  <category>storage-team</category>
  <category>confluence</category>
</page>
